<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Parth Parikh's Blog</title>
        <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blog.html</link>
        <description>Explore the exciting world of Computer Science with me! From the depths of Data Structures and Algorithms to the cutting-edge advancements in NLP and Databases, my blog delves into a wide range of topics to keep you informed and inspired.</description>
        <item>
            <title>What if companies were governed as republics?</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/corporate-republic.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will explore a whitepaper for technology startups, describing a 'mini-republic' corporate charter inspired by some historical constitutional documents and the Roman Republic.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2025</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An Afternoon with SMT, TRIM, and SMART</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/afternoon-smt-trim-smart.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will be diving into the world of SSDs, covering SMT, TRIM, and SMART, plus I'll be geeking out over my MacBook upgrade.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tinker Postman Collector Scribe</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/national-postal-museum.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will explore art, USPS postal technology, philately, and generative art — all inspired by my trip to D.C. last month.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>We’ll buy back your Typewriter ... for Uncle Sam!</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/typewriter-uncle-sam.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will explore another poster I recently bought, which highlights Smith-Corona’s campaign to buy back typewriters for the U.S. government due to wartime shortages during World War II.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 2 Oct 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IBM 305 RAMAC and the 1960 Winter Olympics</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/ibm-ramac-and-1960-winter-olympics.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will explore the IBM 305 RAMAC and its use in the 1960 Winter Olympics.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 3 Sept 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>