<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Parth Parikh's Blog</title>
        <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blog.html</link>
        <description>Explore the exciting world of Computer Science with me! From the depths of Data Structures and Algorithms to the cutting-edge advancements in NLP and Databases, my blog delves into a wide range of topics to keep you informed and inspired.</description>
        <item>
            <title>IBM 305 RAMAC and the 1960 Winter Olympics</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/ibm-ramac-and-1960-winter-olympics.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will explore the IBM 305 RAMAC and its use in the 1960 Winter Olympics.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 3 Sept 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>One Billion Row Challenge in Rust</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/one-billion-row-challenge.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will tackle the One Billion Row Challenge using Rust and Python, converging on a solution in under 10 seconds and looking into some exciting optimizations at play.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Roaring Bitmaps</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/roaring-bitmaps.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we explore Bitmap indexes and their compression techniques, emphasizing their use in databases. We take a look at data structures like Run Length Encoding, Byte-Aligned Bitmap Code, Word-Aligned Hybrid Code, Concise, and Roaring Bitmaps.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tangoing with a Martin Gardner Word Game</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/martin-gardner-game.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we explore a 1969 word game from Martin Gardner. We dive into its computational solving strategies, highlighting the complexity and fun of this NYT-esque puzzle.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Scrambling Eggs for Spotify with Knuth's Fibonacci Hashing</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/fibonacci-hashing.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we explore Spotify's journey from using the Fisher-Yates shuffle to a more sophisticated song shuffling algorithm that prevents clustering of tracks by the same artist. We then connect this challenge to Fibonacci hashing, and propose a novel, evenly distributed artist shuffling method.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>