<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Parth Parikh's Blog</title>
        <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blog.html</link>
        <description>Explore the exciting world of Computer Science with me! From the depths of Data Structures and Algorithms to the cutting-edge advancements in NLP and Databases, my blog delves into a wide range of topics to keep you informed and inspired.</description>
        <item>
            <title>What does Kirchoff, Cayley, and Carroll have in common? And who is Kahrimanian?</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/history-of-trees.html</link>
            <description>This article discusses the three individuals who made early contributions to a mathematical structure that we now know as a tree. We will also see how the tree was introduced in both mathematics and computer science.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Odd Sketches</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/odd-sketches.html</link>
            <description>This article discusses Odd Sketches, a data structure that offers a more precise estimation of Jaccard similarity compared to b-bit minhashing, while also reducing the space complexity significantly compared to standard minhashing techniques.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An architecture for enforcing RBAC in a cloud storage system</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/rbac-storage-system.html</link>
            <description>This article explores a 2016 paper by Garrison et al. that presents an architecture for enforcing access control policies in a cloud storage system.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>KHyperLogLog</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/khyperloglog.html</link>
            <description>This article discusses KHyperLogLog, an algorithm introduced by Google that is based on approximate counting techniques that can estimate certain privacy risks of very large databases using linear runtime and minimal memory.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>