<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Parth Parikh's Blog</title>
        <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blog.html</link>
        <description>Explore the exciting world of Computer Science with me! From the depths of Data Structures and Algorithms to the cutting-edge advancements in NLP and Databases, my blog delves into a wide range of topics to keep you informed and inspired.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Before advanced-flight simulators, there was Navitrainer</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/navitrainer.html</link>
            <description>In this blog post, we will delve into the history of another poster that I recently bought. We will explore the Navitrainer, a precursor to advanced flight simulators. We will investigate its origins, how it works, how it was used, and its crucial role in teaching techniques like dead reckoning to trainee pilots.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sept 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Before Xerox, there was Addressograph</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/addressograph.html</link>
            <description>In this article, we will delve into the history of a poster that I recently bought. Our journey will lead us into the fascinating world of the Addressograph - an early addressing machine, invented by Joseph Smith Duncan in the year 1892.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GADDAG</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/gaddag.html</link>
            <description>This article discusses GADDAG, a data structure for efficiently generating moves in Scrabble using a modified directed acyclic word graph.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Playing Twenty Questions with ChatGPT</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/chatgpt-twenty-questions.html</link>
            <description>Can you play the Twenty Questions game with ChatGPT? In this article, we will see just how well it can play this classic game.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What do Kirchhoff, Cayley, and Carroll have in common? And who is Kahrimanian?</title>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/history-of-trees.html</link>
            <description>All four individuals made interesting early contributions to a mathematical structure that we now know as a tree. In this article, we will briefly explore their unique contributions and see how the tree structure was introduced in both mathematics and computer science.</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>